Guide to the Pacific Geograpic Society Records, 1927-1940
Department of Special Collections
Pacific Geograpic Society Records,
1927-1940
Special Collections M166
Pacific Geographic Society
3 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of N. A. Kovach.
HISTORICAL NOTE
The Pacific Geographic Society was founded in 1926 by Humphrey Read, to be reorganized in 1929 by the president, Walter Gordon Clark, and other officers.
According to the articles of incorporation (July 9, 1929) the following is an outline of the purposes and objectives of the Society:
a) for educational and scientific research pertaining to boundaries of the Pacific Ocean,
b) to promote interests of states and countries bordering on the Pacific Ocean through co-operative membership in education and scientific research,
c) to give publicity to states and countries bordering on the Pacific Ocean, that a better understanding of statehood and citizenship may be realized,
d) to enlighten the world through the publications by members of this corporation,
e) to build, construct, purchase, lease, equip, or otherwise acquire.
Los Angeles served as the center and principal area of business for the enterprise. The corporation there was to "exist fifty years from and after the date of incorporation." In 1932-33 the Globe-Trotter Series of illustrated (motion picture) lectures was initiated, an activity which provided the major source of income of the Society.
Other activities included dinner meetings, often with entertainment for regents, etc., special dinners and receptions, exhibits in libraries and bookstores, selected tours (group and individual) to Mexico, South America, New Zealand and Hawaii. Mrs. Hughes (secretary and manager after the death of Mr. Palmer) often acted as a local booking agent for a number of lecturers, while the Society arranged programs for public schools and libraries, colleges and universities, and other interested organizations.
Several attempts were made to publish a magazine in conjunction with the Society, with no degree of success. A Bulletin and a Newsletter were circulated periodically but the Pacific Geographic Magazine and its successor, Pacific Horizons, began and concluded with Volume I, Number 1.
In 1936 a moratorium agreement with major creditors was effected and the Society is believed to have disbanded in 1940-4l.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Materials in the collection date from 1927-1940, the bulk falling between the years 1933-1939. Included are correspondence, minutes, drafts, reports, statistics, bills, receipts, contracts, clippings, press releases, various lists, organizational papers, announcements, memos, printed brochures, legal papers, itineraries, notes, photos, diagrams, a few maps, pamphlets, some manuscript articles, programs, and invitations.
CONTAINER LIST
- Memos for Board Minute Book 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  drafts & copies of minutes of regular and special meetings; budget 1936-37;copy of agreement proposed with Ray Davidson; annual report & financial statement; signed pledges of money to be loaned to Pacific Geographic Publishing Co.; Globe-Trotter Series budget 1936-37,other financial statistics.
- Abeyance Accounts 1933-34 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  (alphabetical) bills or statements
- Allen, Dr. Arthur A. 1937-38Series (Box 1, Folder 3)
  corresp. re: Allen's motion picture lecture on rare & vanishing birds (Apr. 21, 1938);brochure, photos, etc. incl. officers of Calif. Audubon Society & local branches, 1 T.N.S. of A.A. Allen.
- Bryan, Julien, 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  corresp. with re: lecture series "Inside Nazi Germany" mostly Bryan & Mrs. Hughes (some personal, birth of son) & press releases
- Byrd, Richard E. 1935, 37-39 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  press releases, clips, corresp., tels., re: speaking engagements & interest in peace, radio address (5 T.L.S. Byrd, 2 Tels.)
- Byrd Exhibit 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  corresp. on displays for Alone & Congress on International Good Will, book reviews of Alone (3 Byrd T.L.S.)
- Byrd Replies 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Press Book with short biography, publicity on motion pictures & lecture, etc. replies to Byrd Reception invitations, lists of guests, many prominent persons.
- Board of Regents 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  corresp., lists, acceptances & refusals, articles of incorp. (July 9, 1929);announcements; plans, etc. Pacific Magazine; memos; minutes & report Globe Trotter Series.
- Camera Club, 16 mm. Nov., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  corresp. re: "an amateur movie photographers program
- Craig, Capt. John D. 1937-38 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  brochures (Harold R, Peat, Inc.), photos, corresp. with Peat & others of his office, statement, contract, legal papers.
- Contracts 1937-38 Series (Box 1, Folder 11)
  rental & reservations of auditoriums, contracts with lecturers and managers; Julien Bryan, Wm. B. Feakins, Inc., John D. Craig, Amos Burg, Lee Keedick, Hal Hall, Harry C. Pearson, Harrison Forman, Clark H. Getts, Inc., also contracts with ticket agent & creditors, some corresp.
- Contracts 1937-39 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  with lecturers & managers, Capt. C.W.R. Knight, Wm. B. Feakins, Inc., Julien Bryan, John Hutter, Father Hubbard also auditorium reservations & rentals & some corresp.
- Corresp - Misc. 1937-38 Series (Box 1, Folder 13)
  All 1937,some brochures, 7 clips on lecturers & lecture series, and corresp. re: free motion picture series for school children, lecturers & lectures, teachers Institute Credit, tickets for lectures (about lecturers: Amos Burg, Wilfred L. Husband, Amelia Earhart, Pherbia Thomas, John D. Craig, Harrison Forman)
- Corresp. 1937 Jan -Mar. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  also some 1936,general subject matter re: lecturers, lectures & lecture series, tickets, films, maps, projects, publications, members
- Corresp. 1937 Apr. -May (Box 2, Folder 15)
  general, financial situation, death of Martin Johnson, some undated miscellany
- Corresp. 1937 June -Dec.general (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Corresp. 1938Misc.(actually lists, acceptance cards, clips) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Corresp. 1938 Jan.-Junegeneral (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Corresp. 1938 July -Dec.general (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Corresp. 1939 Jan. -Sept.general (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Edmunds, Charles K. (Pres.) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  1934, 1937 -Jan., 1939corresp re: feasibility of publishing a magazine, exhibits, lectures, lecturers, Globe Trotter Series, Robert Ripley suit, Barclay Acheson, meetings, members, finan. report, general business
- Feakins, William B. (booking agent) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  1937-38corresp. & brochures re: lectures of Julian Bryan, C.W.R. Knight -promotional material & info on others -added July 7, 1970
- Gaumer, Alfred Elliott (Box 3, Folder 23)
  corresp. 1937re: field trip -examination, excavation & collecting in Basket Maker Caves in the Desolation Canyon of the Green River. Lists of equipment, etc. plans only, expedition did not go.
- Gause, M. Jeannette (manager & booking agent) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  l935, 1937-38Series corresp., brochures, (all 1937)on Alan Villiers, J.E. Williamson, Ruth Bryan, Owen & Michail M. Dorizas, Amos Burg.
- Getts, Clark H. (manager) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  corresp. re: brochures, photos and press publicity on Mrs. Osa Johnson, Harrison Forman (particularly)
- Globe Trotter Series Lists 1932-33 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  primarily mailing lists, 2 ltrs., clip, ptd. World Affairs Dinner proceedings
- Globe Trotter Series 1938-39 & 1939-40 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  photos, corresp, with or about lecturers, sponsors & booking agents, brochures. map, 1936& misc. brochures, etc. actual dates 1936, 1938-39
- Globe Trotter Series Registered Information (Box 3, Folder 28)
  1932-35corresp., itins. for Mexican Tours Mexican travel brochures, Central American Tour itin., reservations, bills, receipts
- Hubbard, Father Bernard R.S.J. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  re: lecture corresp. mostly with sec., typescript background on King Islanders & Father Lafortune 1938-39(1 ltr. & 1 tel. from Hubbard)
- Invitations Completed (Box 3, Folder 30)
  re: 1932membership campaign. Have kept a few letters showing how campaign was carried out & a few lists as examples of the type & scope of the proposed members & 1930 event
- Johnson, Mrs. Martin (Box 3, Folder 31)
  1938corresp. with C.H. Getts, mgr., bills & receipts, rental contract, publicity & promotional material & distribution list. Shows expense & method of putting on a lecture.
- Keedick, Lee (manager) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  1935, 1937 -corresp., brochures, etc., on Amos Burg
- Kellaway Magazine Matter (Box 3, Folder 33)
  1938proposal for an official magazine for the society, corresp.
- Local Lecture Material 1930-41 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  (with gaps & undated items), brochures (some with comments), notes, photos, letters, clips.
- Long Beach Chapter (Box 4, Folder 35)
  1929-31corresp. re: extension of activities
- Long Beach 1933-34 Series (&1931) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  corresp, 1932-34,lists, diagrams, membership card, bills, statistics, advance reservation form, notes.
- Los Angeles Chapter (Box 4, Folder 37)
  1929-31corresp. re: members, programs, bills, publicity
- Los Angeles Public Library Programs (Box 4, Folder 38)
  1933-34corresp. re: lectures, exhibits
- Maps (Box 4, Folder 39)
  1936orders for facsimiles of Heylin map
- Martin, Dr. Howard H. (Box 4, Folder 40)
  1931corresp. re: representing P.G. society at International Geographical Congress in Paris
- Membership Acceptances (Box 4, Folder 41)
  1930-33letters incl. George Herbert Harris, V.L. Duke, Frank W. Miller, Charles A. Lindbergh, Lady M. Richmond Jones, Elias Almeyda Arroyo, Count Louis Hamon & Ernest Walker Sawyer
- Membership - Sustaining, Declines. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  1938-39ltrs. incl. Rockwell D. Hunt, Dana W. Bartlett, Roy A. Henley, Carl Sumner Knopf
- Mexican Tours 1932 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  corresp., lists, itinerary, brochures
- Mexican Tour 1936 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  corresp., lists, itinerary 1935-36
- Mexican Tour 1937-38 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  brochures, corresp., itinerary
- Moratorium Accounts (Box 4, Folder 46)
  Statements of creditors 1931-34who formed moratorium with Society in 1936 (see correspondence)
- Newsletter Material 1935-36 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  news releases, pamphlets, information bulletins, clips, corresp., photos, announcements, subscription, ins. articles, dummies, H.E. House ms.
- Newsletter Material 1935-36 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  same type of material as above -brochures, lists, scientific & educational -Pacific littoral
- New Zealand Tour 1932-33 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  itinerary, T.L.S. of Adam Hamilton (Prime Minister's Office)
- O'Connor, Arthur H. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  corresp. 1933-35radio program, lecture, Balboa Day Exhibit, Australian dinner
- Officers (Box 5, Folder 52)
  lists, corres., office report to Board of Directors, brochures 1933-35elections, duties, finances, G-T series etc., general business
- Orange County Chapter 1929-30 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  gen. corresp. re: program & location
- Pacific Discovery Day 1934 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  corresp, 2 undated news releases, subs. F.D.R. radio address, P.G.S. reception, copy of proclamation by F.F. Merriam, Gov. of Calif.
- Pacific Discovery Day 1937 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  corresp. incl. invitation & acceptances
- Pacific Discovery Day 1938 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  corresp. 1938-39,pamphlet re: 425th anniversary Balboa statue, Smithsonian radio program script for radio show on Balboa
- Pacific Geographic Magazine 1929-31 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  corresp., Read's debts & actions, memos & notes, minutes, resignation of Read, map, some undated material, bills & miscellany.
- Pacific Magazine 1933- (Box 5, Folder 58)
  corresp., pamphlets, brochures, article on Cardenas, notes
- Pan American Day 1938 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  corresp., brochure, circulars
- Pasadena Chapter 1930-31 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  list of members, corresp, bills, programs
- Pearson, Harry C. 1937-38series (Box 5, Folder 61)
  news releases, brochures, corresp., photos, clips. re: film and lecture "African Holiday"
- Peat, Harold (mgr. & booking agent) (Box 5, Folder 62)
  1935corresp., brochures re: Ruroy Sibley, R.E. Fulton, Jr., Sasha Siemel, Father Hubbard, Lowell Thomas, Capt. Noville, Alexander Markey, Bruce Bairnsfather, etc.
- Peng-Chun Chang's Dinner Mar. 22, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  invitation, replies (acceptances followed by regrets), lists
- Pepperdine, George (Box 5, Folder 64)
  1934lists, corresp.
- Philharmonic Auditorium Reports (Box 5, Folder 65)
  1933-34statistics, bills, some corresp.
- Pillsbury, Arthur C. 1935-36 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  corresp., photos, press releases, use of timelapse photography in plant study, lecture
- Pomona College 1929, 32-33 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  Pac. Geoge Soc. by-laws and minutes, corresp., outline Murphy lectures
- Pond, James B. (lecture tour manager) (Box 5, Folder 69)
  1932-34corresp., contracts re: Lucille Douglass, William Beebe, Robert Shippee, Upton Close, bank shutdown
- Program Material 1939-40 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  1938-39corresp., brochures
- Putnam, George Palmer (Box 6, Folder 71)
  1937-38 series: 1937corresp, re: Earhart lecture
- Public School Contracts 1932-33 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  corresp. re: lecture series, Sherer in particular
- Receipts Misc. (Box 6, Folder 73)
  shows types of expenses & variety also includes examples of work & lecture contracts
- Re-Organization 1927-29 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  corresp., Honorary Life Fellowship Certificate, clips., ptd. speech and other material, background info, minutes
- Requested Information 1936 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  notes & requests re: magazine, Globe Trotter Series, tickets, etc.
- Resignations 1929 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  as directors, officers, regents, board & reg. Members
- Rice, George, Receipts 1934 (Box 6, Folder 77)
- San Diego Chapter 1929-30, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  corres., lists, clip., publicity re: Chinese dinner
- San Diego Lecture Information Requests 1936 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  corres., & forms
- San Diego Material 1935-36 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  corresp., clips., misc. re: Byrd lecture & others
- Sawders, James (Box 6, Folder 81)
  1933-35corresp., tels., list or synopsis re: lectures
- Sekku - Boys' Day (Japanese) 1935 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  corresp. re: lst Boys' Day Festival held in L.A.; clips. in Japanese
- Slipper Co., Receipts (Box 6, Folder 83)
- South American Tour 1937 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  postcard requests, 1 carbon of letter
- Southern California Music Co. Ticket Office 1933-36 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  corresp., receipts, statements, notes -shows expenses, income, seating etc. for various lectures
- Southern California Music Co. Ticket Office 1936-38 (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Speakers' Agency 1936 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  announcements, brochures, corresp., photos, stats., lists re: lectures & lecturers
- Stacy-Judd Lecture 1931 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  corresp., photos, brochures
- Subscription Fund 1931-33 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  bills or pledges
- Subscription Lists 1935-36 (Box 7, Folder 90)
- Terriss, Tom File 1933-34 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  corresp., brochures re: lectures, fees also on Carl Von Hoffman
- Tour Information Requests 1935-36 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  corresp., notes
- U.S.C. Series 1933-35 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  corresp., notes, lists, statistics, brochures
- Ware, Carolyn (manager) 1933-35 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  corresp., & brochures re: lecturers Burton Holmes, Upton Close, Syud Hossain, A.C. Pillsbury, etc.
- Wells, Carveth 1933 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  corresp., clip., brochures, news release
- Wigman Program 1933 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  corresp., bills, receipts, contracts, tax documents, brochures re: Mary Wigman performance
- Wilshire Ebell Theater (Box 7, Folder 97)
  1938-39corresp.
- Wilson, Elmer (Box 7, Folder 98)
  Report 1937-38 Series, lists, statistics, some corresp.
- World Affairs Session 1938 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  ptd. program, report, agenda, corresp.
PARTIAL INDEX OF CORRESPONDENCE AND MAJOR SUBJECTS
(1) indicates only one letter
(m) indicates mentioned in
Aicher, John W.H. 1899-(Am. fin. corp. offl.) Folder 41
Alexander, Hartley Burr 1873-(Am. univ. prof.) Folder 21,27
Allen, Arthur Augustus 1885-(Am. ornithologist) Folder 3 (1)
Andrews, Roy Chapman 1884-(zoologist, explorer) Folder 58
Armitage, Merle 1893-(Am. impresario) Folder 27,65
Arthur, James B. 1889-(sales mgr.) Folder 42 (1)
Atherton, Frank Cooke 1877-(Am. fin. exec. -Hawaii) Folder 41 (1)
Baird, William S. 1856-(mun. judge) Folder 42 (1)
Balboa Day see Pacific Discovery Day
Ballard, Russell Henry 1875-(uti. operator) Folder 76
Bandini, Elliott 1894-(advertising man) Folder 42 (1)
Barkam, Frank Forrest 1879-(Am. publisher) Folder 41,45
Barker, George C. Folder 15,16
Barrett, Samuel Alfred 1879-(Am. anthropologist) Folder 14,87
Bartlett, Dana Webster 1860-(clergyman) Folder 42 (1)
Baumgardt, B.R. 1862-(Am. scientist -astron. & math.) Folder 38
Beach, Lansing Hoskins 1860-(army officer) Folder 63
Beaman, Alexander Gaylord Emmons 1885-(insurance) Folder 42 (1)
Bernard, Robert J. (Pomona College) Folder 15,16,20,22,61,87
Blakeslee, Francis Durbin 1846-1942 (Am. educator, lecturer, newspaper corr.) Folder 37
Bledsoe, Benjamin Franklin 1874-1938 (attorney) Folder 42 (1)
Bloch, Claude Charles 1878-(Am. naval officer -admiral) Folder 7
Booth, Franklin 1874-(Am. illustrator) Folder 16
Bowen, William Miller 1862-(attorney) Folder 7 (1)
Bowman, Edith M. (PGS Speaker's Agency) Folder 87
Bowman, Michael L. (Pacific Geog. Soc. Speakers Agency) Folder 27,81,87
Boys' Day see Sekku
Braunschweiger, Walter J. (PGS director -bd.) Folder 52,82
Brehm, James R. 1883-(investment broker) Folder 63
Bronson, Dillon 1863-(clergyman) Folder 63
Bryan, Julien (Am. [photographer-newsman?]) Folder 4,11,12,22
Burdette, Clara Bradley 1855-(clubwoman) Folder 58
Burg, Amos Folder (m) 11,13,24,32
Byrd, Richard Evelyn 1888-(Am. polar explorer) Folder 5,6,7 (m)
Carruthers, John Franklin Bruce 1889-(educator) Folder 8,57
Chandler, Harry 1864-(newspaper pub.) Folder 8 (1)
Chandler, Norman 1899-(newspaperman) Folder 52 (1)
Clark, Vinnie B. Folder 8,57,76,78
Clark, Walter Gordon (pres. PGS) Folder 8,74
Clements, George P. 1867-(agri. economist) Folder 8,37,57,74,82
Close, Upton 1894-(real name: Josef Washinton Hall) (author, lecturer) Folder 69, (m) 94
Cluverius, Wat Tyler 1874-(naval officer) Folder 7 (1)
Coffield, Kathryn Folder 14,15,27,29,87
Cole, George Watson 1850-(bibliog. librarian) Folder 42
Cookman, Alfred 1891-(educator, lecturer) Folder 8,53,57,76
Corbin, William Lee 1872-(librarian) Folder 17
Craig, John D. 10(m), 11(m), Folder 13 (m)
Cravens, John Smith 1871-(banker) Folder 55,63
Crawford, Will C. (school Supt.) Folder 27,79,80,87
Crocker, Adelaide P. Folder 7,63
Cruickshank, Lewis 1884-(attorney) Folder 57,74
Davidson, Gilbert Aubrey 1868-(banker) Folder 7,76
Davidson, Ray Folder 1 (m),21,28
Day, Arthur Louis 1869-(physicist) Folder 76
Doheny, Edward Lawrence 1856-(petroleum producer) Folder 8 (1)
Earhart, Amelia 1898-1937 (aviation) Folder 13 (m), 71 (m)
Early, Stephen 1889-(asst. to Pres. F.D.R.) Folder 54 (1)
Edmunds, Charles Keyser 1876-(college pres.) Folder 8,21,27,52,57,68,87,99
Elliott, H.W. (v.p. PGS) Folder 21,52,65
Elliott, John B. 1878-(oil corp. offl.) Folder 63
Emmons, Frederick E. Folder 14,19,28,44,45
Emmons, George Edward 1857-(manufacturer) Folder 55,63 (1)
Farrand, Max 1869-(library director) Folder 63
Feakins, William B. (lecture Mgr.) Folder 11,12,14,22
Firth, R.M. (New Zealand gov't. cmmr.) Folder 7,14,48,49
Fleischman, Max C. 1877-(mfr.) Folder 8,57
Forbes, Mrs. Armitage S.C. Folder 41,76
Ford, Willard Stanley 1890-(educator) Folder 27
Forman, Harrison Folder 11 (m), 13 (m), 25,87
Fowler, William Eric 1875-(lawyer, statesman) Folder 8,76
Gale, Edmund Waller 1884-(cartoonist) Folder 16 (1)
Garland, William May 1866-(realtor) Folder 8,82
Gaumer, Alfred Elliott [geol. or archeol.?] Folder 14,18,23
Gause, M. Jeannette Folder 24,27
Gessler, Clifford Franklin 1893-(writer, editor) Folder 21
Ghetts, Clark H. Folder 11,20,25,27,31,87
Gifford, Robert Ladd 1867-(consulting engr.) Folder 63
Gillette, Edwin Fraser 1863-(architect) Folder 63
Gingrich, Arnold 1903-(editor, author) Folder 16 (1)
Globe-Trotter Series Folder 1,3,4,5,7,8,11,12,13,21,22,24,25,26,27,28,29,31,32,35,36,37,51,52,53,65,66,67,68,69,7O,71,75,79,80,81,85, 86,87,88,91,94,95,97,98
Green, Edward Craft (sec. PGS) Folder 8,37,57,76
Grosvenor, Melville Bell (Nat'l. Geographic) Folder 16,27 (copy)
Hadley, Anna B. Folder 14 (1)
Hall, Josef Washington see Close, Upton
Hammond, Wilmer Mitchell 1877-(ins. gen. agent) Folder 19,42
Hampton, Edgar Lloyd 1872-(writer) Folder 57,76
Hancock, G(eorge) Allan 1875-(banker, oil operator) Folder 15 (1)
Hanna, Byron Calvin 1887-(lawyer) Folder 7 (1)
Harrington, Mark Raymond 1882-(anthropologist) Folder 34
Harris, Frederic Robert 1875-(ret. rear adm.) Folder 7,63
Harris, George Herbert (army officer) Folder 41
Hartog, Adrian (Netherlands consul) Folder 7,54,88
Harwood, Edward Charles 1872-(citrus grower) Folder 63
Haymond, William H.B. 1897-(attorney) Folder 42
Helms, Elmer Ellsworth 1863-(clergyman) Folder 7 (1)
Hepburn, Arthur Japy 1877-(naval officer) Folder 7 (1)
Hertzog, Walter Sylvester 1881-(historian, educator) Folder 57,76
Hilton, William Atwood 1878-(zoologist) Folder 21
Hodge, Frederick Webb 1864-(ethnologist) Folder 27
Holmes, (Elias) Burton 1870-(travel-lecturer) Folder 27
Holmes, Ralston Smith 1882-(naval officer) Folder 7 (1)
Hoyt, Minerva Hamilton 1866-(conservationist) Folder 57 (1)
Hubbard, Bernard Rosecrans 1888-(priest, explorer, author) Folder 12 (m),14,29, 62 (m)
Hughes, Margaret E. (sec., mgr. PGS) almost all outgoing corresp. and specifically Folder 1,21,52
Hughes, Rupert 1872-(author) Folder 55
Hunt, Rockwell Dennis 1868-(univ. dean) Folder 7,8,42,57,89
Husband, Wilfred L. Folder 10
Hutter, John Folder 10,27
Johnson, Milbank 1971-(physician, social economist) Folder 8,57,74,76
Johnson, Osa (Mrs. Martin) Folder 25 (m),31 (m)
Johnson, Paul Franklin Folder 9,15,16,55,74
Jones, Mattison Boyd 1869-(attorney) Folder 41,42
Jordan, David Starr (univ. pres.) Folder 8 (1)
Keedick, Lee 1879-(lyceum mgr.) Folder 11,20,27,32
Kellogg, Edward R. 1869-(surgeon) Folder 41 (1)
Kiewit, Ralph W. Folder 6,7,44,52,82
KleinSmid, Rufus Bernard von 1875-(psychologist, univ. press) Folder 7,8,15,19,82
Knopf, Carl Sumer 1889-(educator, lecturer) Folder 19,21,42
Koster, Frederick Jacob 1868-(barrel Mfgr.) Folder 41 (1)
Kurtz, Edward M. 1872-(corpn. offl., engr.) Folder 7,63
Lahey, May D. (municipal judge) Folder 41 (1)
Lesser, Sol 1890-(theatre owner) Folder 41 (1)
Lindbergh, Charles Augustus 1902-(aviator) Folder 41 (1)
Lissauer, Herman Folder 65 (1)
Lissner, Henry H. Folder 42 (1)
Lloyd, Ralph B. 1875-(oil operator, realtor, banker) Folder 7 (1)
Lockwood, Hanford Nicholas 1859-(lawyer) Folder 63
Long Beach Chapter Folder 35,36
Los Angeles Chapter Folder 37
Macomber, Laurence 1885-(lawyer) Folder 63
Mc Bride, George M. Folder 7,8,17
Mc Curdy, Robert M. Folder 10,16,19,27,96
Mc Fadden, H.M. Folder 10,13,14,62
Mc Garry, Daniel Francis 1873-(realtor) Folder 42 (1)
Martin, Harold H. 1879-(architect) Folder 7 (1),40
Matson, Clarence H. 1872-(chamber commerce offl.) Folder l4
Mattison, Fitch C.E. 1861-(physician, surgeon) Folder 8,57,74
Merriam, Frank Finley 1865-(Gov. of Calif.) Folder 7 (1)
Mexican Tours Folder 43,44,45
Miller, Frank William (supt. instruction) Folder 41 (1)
Monnette, Orra Eugene 1873-(banker, lawyer) Folder 8,76
Monsen, Courtenay (sec. PGS) Folder 8,l4,20,28,52,60
Moore, Charles Irwin Douglas 1865-(ins. offl.) Folder 42 (1)
Moore, Robert Thomas 1882-(scientist) Folder l,l8,52,58
Moss, John R. Folder 85,86
Mudd, Harvey Seeley 1888-(mining engr.) Folder 21 (1)
Mullendore, William Clinton 1892-(lawyer) Folder 42 (1)
Munro, William Bennett 1875-(educator) Folder 21,63
Newlin, Gurney Elwood 1880-(lawyer) Folder 8,74
Newsletter Folder 47,48,49
New Zealand Tour Folder 50